一说起侦察卫星
When you think of surveillance satellites
你可能会想到给政府秘密情报部门随时传送任意地点高清图片的卫星
you think of systems beaming back high-res images of almost anywhere on earth to secret government intelligence agencies
但现在这种技术已经家喻户晓，比如谷歌地球就有类似功能
but now that same technology is also available for all of us with things like Google Earth
但人类最早的侦察卫星发射的时候，用的技术可原始多了
However when the very first surveillance satellites were launched things were really quite a lot more primitive
那时候可根本没有电子技术能把图像传回地球
and you could forget about electronically beaming images back to earth
那他们是怎么把照片弄回来，这些技术又是怎样影响阿波罗工程的呢
So how did they get the images back and how did this affect missions like Apollo
冷战时期，美国和其他西方国家面对的一个最大的难题
In the Cold War era one of the biggest problems for the US and the West in general
是对苏联和当时的中国情报了解不足
was just not knowing what was going on in the Soviet Union and to a similar extent Communist China
丘吉尔也不会无缘无故说“一道横贯欧洲大陆的铁幕已经降落下来”
not for nothing did Churchill say that an Iron Curtain has descended across the Europe
二战中盟军依靠空中侦察来了解德国的进展
In World War II the Allies relied upon airborne reconnaissance to see what the Germans were up to
而德国的很多秘密武器，比如V-2火箭、V-1火箭
and many of the secret weapons like the V-2 rocket and a V-1 flying bomb
都是从空中拍摄的照片揭露的
were uncovered by aerial photos
但西欧相比于苏联还是太小了
But Western Europe is small in comparison to the Soviet Union
把西欧整个扔进苏联领土里都找不到在哪
you could drop it in the middle of a Soviet Union and not know it was there at all
虽然美国在1946年就开始了对苏联边境的空中侦察
Although the U.S. started aerial reconnaissance along the Soviet borders in 1946
但是直到1950年朝鲜战争爆发，对苏联空军的情报需求才真正增加
it was the start of a Korean War in 1950 which brought home the need for more information on the Soviet Air Force
包括其军事能力以及是否有对美国发动核武器突然袭击的能力
and its capabilities and if it could mount a surprise bomber attack with nuclear weapons on the US
美国开始研发高空飞行器
High-altitude overflights were gradually built up
先是B-52的前任B-47，然后又有了洛马的U-2侦察机
First with a Boeing B-47 a predecessor to the B-52 and later with the lockheed U-2 spy plane
还有些其他的空中侦察方法比如Genetrix计划
There had also been other aerial surveillance methods like Project Genetrix
使用氦气球携带相机飞到十万英尺高空
which used helium balloons to carry cameras at heights of up to a 100,000 feet
借西风横跨苏联和中国
and blown by the westerly winds across the Soviet Union China
但只有约6%的气球能回收到可用的图像，别的不是被击落就是飞偏
But only around 6% of these were recovered with usable images the rest were either shot down or blown off-course
显然美国急需一种更安全更快速的办法
Clearly a better safer method was needed and quickly
1960年，加里·鲍尔斯的U-2侦察机被苏联击落，导致严重外交事件
In 1960 Gary Powers U-2 spy plane was shot down over the Soviet Union causing a major diplomatic incident
这使得美国不得不放弃空中侦察，但这个问题他们早有准备
and forcing the U.S. to suspend over flights but the problem had also been anticipated
CIA里负责U-2侦察机的启动了科罗娜计划
The CIA who also ran the U-2 spy planes headed up a project called Corona
内容是把相机安装在160公里高的近地轨道卫星上
and have been working on put in a camera into a satellite in a low Earth orbit 160 kilometers above the Earth
这个高度苏联防御系统毫无办法
There it would be safe from any Soviet defences
而卫星时速27000公里，使其可以短时间内拍摄极大范围内的领土
and of a speed at which it traveled some 27,000 km/h they could image huge tracts of land in a very short space of time
把相机放上卫星最大的问题是当时还没有送物体入轨
The problem with putting a camera in space was up until then no one had actually launched something into orbit
并让其安全返回地球回收的技术
and then safely recovered it back to earth
你可能会问为啥不送相机上去把图像传回来
Now you may well ask why didn't they just use video cameras and beam the images back
因为当时人类还没这项科技点
but that kind of technology just wasn't ready
这项技术是20年后的70年代才出现的
and it wouldn't be until the late 1970s almost 20 years later
之后才有高清数字图像画质
足够好到可用于情报收集的事情
before high-resolution digital imagery would be good enough for intelligence gathering
1976年哈勃太空望远镜的前身KH-11
成为美国第一个数字光学侦察卫星
所以他们的办法是把拍过的胶卷放进带隔热罩的小舱内送回地球
So the idea they came up with was to drop the exposed film from orbit in a heat shield bucket back to earth
让它落回太平洋，并在15000英尺高空用飞机勾住其降落伞
over the Pacific Ocean and then catch its parachute over planes at about 15,000 feet
刚听可能感觉太酷炫了，但实际上飞机回收是项目里最简单的部分
Now it might sound like a crazy idea but catching it with a plane was actually the easy part
这个在之前Genetrix项目里回收气球就干过
and they've done it before with the Genetrix surveillance balloons
难点在于让胶卷舱准确落到飞机等待的区域
the difficult part was getting the film bucket to be in the same area as the waiting planes
项目为了保密，不让人们问太多范登堡军事基地试飞次数的问题
To keep the program secret and stop people from asking too many questions about the number of test flights
from Vandenberg Air Force Base
人们最初称此项目为“发现者”
it was initially called Discoverer
对外声称卫星是送小动物进入轨道以用于研究
the cover story being that the satellites were carrying small animals into orbit for research
然后让它们返回地球，研究经过发射和待在太空所受到的影响
and then being dropped back to earth to see how they were affected by the launch and being in space
但实际上真正带的东西只有相机
but the only things we were really carrying were cameras
在太空拍照再送胶卷回来是一个难点
The idea of taking pictures from space and then getting them back was one thing
但在50年代后期光是把最新研发的雷神-阿金纳火箭
but in the late 1950s just getting the newly developed Thor-Agena rocket
安全飞离发射台就已经很难了
safely off the launch pad was another
整整经历12次尝试，终于在1960年8月10日
It took 12 attempts before on August the 10th 1960
发现者13号让人类第一次把物体从近地轨道回收
Discoverer 13 became the first man-made object to be safely recovered from space
比苏联用史泼尼克2号完成同样的事情早了九天
nine days before the Soviets did the same with the Korabl Sputnik 2
在持续到发现者39号的测试期过后
After the testing period which lasted up until Discoverer 39
项目名称又改回叫科罗娜，并被标为最高机密，直到1992年才解密
the program's name reverting back to Corona and it was classified as top secret and remained that way until 1992
与现在的卫星能在轨好几年不同
Unlike the satellites of today which stay in orbit for years
科罗娜卫星设计只能在轨最多几周
the Corona ones were only intended to be there for maybe a few weeks most
一旦胶卷拍完，剩余部分的卫星就没用了，因为胶卷没法补充
Once the film have been exposed and returned the rest of a satellite was no longer needed and they couldn't refill it
所以它也成为世界上最贵的胶卷相机
so it became the world's most expensive disposable camera system
每个科罗娜卫星使用两台全景相机，每台带有610毫米焦距镜头
Each Corona satellite used 2 panoramic cameras each with 610 millimeter focal length lenses
使用70毫米胶片，解析度相当于每毫米170行
and they used 70 millimeter film that had a resolution of a 170 lines per millimeter
是二战中侦察用的最好的胶片的两倍
twice that of the best film used for world war ii reconnaissance
两个相机可以做到立体画面的拍摄
Two cameras enabled stereographic imaging to be done
图像技术人员可以以此评估地面物体的深度、尺寸等信息
allowing the image technicians to better gauge the depth and size of objects seen on the ground
卫星没有采取从轨道直接向下拍单独一张照片的办法
Instead of taking just simple snapshots with the cameras looking straight down from orbit
而是镜头带着胶卷条沿着70度的弧线划过
the lenses exposed the filmstrip as it moved through a 70 degree arc
这样可移动的镜头可以避免卫星高速运行带来的运动模糊
This moving lens was to avoid the movement blur caused by the speed of a satellite
并能得到下方地面几乎一长条连续的画面
and to get an almost continuous image strip of the ground below
从而最大化利用胶卷
making the maximum use of a film available
为了防止镜头转动归位时带来的扭矩影响卫星的姿态
To stop the torque reaction of the lens as it returned to the starting position from up setting the satellites orientation
新版本中镜头更重的下半部分会继续旋转作为抵消扭矩的“配重”
the lower heavier part of the lens on later models continuously rotated to act as a counterbalance
这些镜头都是使用最好的材料，是当时人类制造过的最完美的镜片
The lenses themselves were made from the finest materials and at a time were the most perfectly ground lenses ever made
卫星运行轨道很接近极地轨道，就是说它们是南北运行的
The satellites operated in a nearly polar orbit meaning they traveled almost north to south
轨道刚好能每圈偏移几度
where the orbit offset just enough so that it would move a few degrees further around the globe with each orbit
为了准确判断物体大小
In order to accurately judge the size of objects
人们在亚利桑那州卡萨格兰德建了一组水泥刻度标志
a set of concrete calibration targets were created on the ground around Casa Grande in Arizona
可以轻松在太空发现
that could be easily seen from space
每个形状是个十字，直径约18米
Each one was a shape of a maltese cross and about 18 meters in diameter
其中256个以1英里(1.65公里)间距被放置在的16×16英里的地方
256 of them were placed exactly one mile apart or 1.65 kilometers in a 16 by 16 mile grid
虽然它们在1972年项目结束的时候废弃了
Although they were abandoned in 1972 when the program came to an end
但其中143个到2018年仍在那里
some 143 of them were still in position as of 2018
科罗娜计划最初，最好的分辨率在7米左右
At the beginning of the Corona program the best resolution that could be seen was around 7 meters
但之后相机和胶卷的连续几次升级改进
but with continual updates and improvements in both the film and the cameras
到了项目晚期，精度达到了一米半
by the program's end it was down to one and a half meters
胶卷的需求提升还导致聚酯胶卷的诞生
The amount of film also increased as new thinner polyester based films were developed
它们更能耐受太空的严酷条件
that were also much more tolerant of a harsh conditions in space
同样环境会导致早期醋酸酯胶卷出现破损
something which had plagued the earlier acetate films with breakages
在项目晚期，每个卫星有两个分开的胶卷舱
By the end of the program each satellite had two separate film buckets
每个有4900米的胶卷，可以送回一个后再继续使用另一个
each containing up to 4900 metres of film allowing one to be dropped off whilst the other was still in use
当胶卷拍完、任务目标被发现
Once the film had been exposed and the mission objectives had been covered
胶卷会在一个可分离隔热罩的保护下从卫星弹出
it will be ejected from a satellite protected by a detachable heat shield
在大约60000英尺高空打开减速伞
at around 60,000 feet a drogue parachute was deployed
然后是主伞，下降到15000英尺高空
before then the main chutes carried it down to around 15,000 feet
最终被尾巴带着抓钩的飞机钩走
It will be captured by planes trailing an airborne claw
随后胶卷舱会被拉回机舱内
which when winched the bucket onboard the plane
这个空中回收方法相当成功
This method of airborne recovery became so successful
使其在之后80年代后期的侦察系统中仍在发挥功用
that it continued to be used on subsequent reconnaissance systems well into the late 1980s
中国的侦察卫星也是将类似的方法使用到了2000年
and the Chinese were still using a similar system for their spy satellites up until the 2000s
如果飞机错过了胶卷舱，或者因为某些原因偏航落入大海
If a plane missed the film bucket or for some reason it was off course and landed in the sea
底部的盐栓会溶解于海水，在两天后让整个胶卷舱沉入大海
it was fitted with a salt plug which would dissolve after two days and sink the bucket
以防止让它随意漂流被外国势力捡走
rather let it float around in the sea and possibly be captured by a foreign power
但科罗娜不仅仅是侦察卫星
But Corona was more than just a spy satellite
它还成为了某些关键技术的测试台
it became a testbed for some of the key technologies
并在将来应用到双子座、水星、阿波罗计划中
that will be used in programs like Gemini, Mercury and Apollo
从再入大气、到定点溅落
from the re-entry of the Earth's atmosphere at a specific point to splashdown
以及海上定点回收，都为那些任务积累了经验
and recovery from the sea at a predefined area in the ocean
到1972年，科罗娜计划一共成功回收167次
By 1972 Corona had done a 167 successful recoveries
总共拍摄了超过9.2亿平方公里的陆地照片
and photograph over 920 million square kilometers of land
该计划拍摄的照片影响了60年代后所有美国海外军事政策
The photos the program took affected every major US overseas military policy of 1960s and beyond
并阻止了美苏两国在50年代遗留的大量不信任所可能带来的过度反应
and stopped much of the overreaction but had caused much of a mistrust between the U.S. and the Soviets in the 1950s
卫星侦察技术成为了双方核裁军条约的奠基石
Satellite reconnaissance became the cornerstone of nuclear disarmament treaties for both sides
双方把拆解的轰炸机摆在露天场所让对方能从太空看到
with chopped-up bombers left in the open for the other side to see from space
在1992年解密后
After it was Declassified in 1992
它的档案揭露了相当多的人类历史遗迹和自然景观
its archives revealed much more about the natural world and our ancient history than had been seen from the air before
即使是现在，它们扔被用来观察几十年来人类对世界做出的影响
and even now they are still used to see the effect that we have had on the world
over the decades since these photos were taken
字幕翻译给虫，欢迎点赞投币收藏转发分享评论关注充电~
所以你对早期的侦察卫星把照片带回地球采取的方法有何看法
So what do you think of the early despising the sky and their ingenious methods they used to get the images back to earth
可以顺便看看CuriousDroid频道的其他视频
Don't forget to check out some of our other videos
最后感谢观看，欢迎点赞分享
and it just remains for me to say thanks for watching and please subscribe thumbs up and share